Alexinder Virdee

Miami, FL | (954) 616-9029 | alex@virdee.com

alexvirdee.com | LinkedIn.com/in/alexvirdee | github.com/alexvirdee

Profile

A Miami based software developer with a passion for creating new and exciting applications. Obtaining my bachelor's degree at the University of Central Florida I work hard to solve difficult problems. Currently I have two years of experience working in the healthcare industry with a focus on front-end software development. I am excited, and look forward to a new opportunity that will contribute to the continuous development of my programming skills.

Technical Skills

JavaScript, Java, Angular, Express.js, MongoDB, SQL, Node.js, SPARQL, RDF, Ember, React, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Grunt, AJAX, jQuery, Responsive Design, Tailwinds, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, Wordpress, Typescript.

Professional Experience

Web Application Developer

April 2018 - January 2020

INFOTECHSoft, Inc.

Miami, FL

- Web Developer tasked to the GeneTegra Platform Data Lakes and Baptist Health Projects committed to advancing biomedical research in the health-care industry
- Utilized semantic web technologies such as SPARQL, RDF, and OWL to aggregate and query vast amounts of biomedical data
- Prepared and developed UX/UI mockup proposals using Balsamiq wireframing software successfully iterating, creating, and producing client specific designs
- Tasked with developing and enhancing features for company applications primarily with the JavaScript web development framework Ember.js
- Worked through complex problem solving and fixed issues assigned through Jira improving client retention rates
- Worked closely with back-end engineers linking Java applications to company front-end interfaces
- Used user input to develop, iterate, and ship applications in a swift efficient manner
- Skilled in the software development life cycle, achieving higher overall quality of applications by appropriately employing Kanban methodology

Teaching Assistant

May 2018 - August 2018

University of Miami

Miami, FL

- Worked closely with students to help them understand and program the basic fundamentals of JavaScript and front-end technologies
- Developed trust and rapport with class to code applications starting with design and building REST APIs with NodeJS & front-end user interfaces with React

Education

Ironhack

January 2018 - March 2018

Miami, FL

• Ironhack is an immersive web development bootcamp. The program has a fast paced setting with a highly selective cohort of students.

Projects Built

Paper Droid

 An interactive JavaScript based arcade shooter game that uses collision logic and keyboard inputs

Divex

• A server side scuba diving web application with authorization for a personal diving logbook

M5Power

 A BMW forums application for enthusiasts of the BMW M series to make posts and chat with other users

University of Central Florida

Orlando, FL

August 2012 - August 2016

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration - Management, Entrepreneurial Track